Jordan Boyd-Graber

Jordan.Boyd.Graber@colorado.edu • +1 (920) 524-9464 • http://cs.colorado.edu/~jbg 111B ECCS • Computer Science • Engineering Center • Boulder, CO 80309

Summary

Jordan Boyd-Graber's research focus is in applying machine learning and Bayesian probabilistic models to problems that help us better understand social interaction or human cognition. His research applies statistical models to natural language problems in ways that interact with humans, learn from humans, or help researchers understand humans.

Jordan is an expert in the application of topic models,

completely automatic tools that can discover structure and meaning in large, multilingual datasets. He is a contributor to the Natural Language Toolkit (NLTK), a popular Python package. His work has been supported by NSF, IARPA, and ARL.

He received a NIPS Best Paper award honorable mention, a Computing Innovation Fellowship (declined), and a Jorgensen fellowship. His Erdös number is 2.

Positions Held

University of Colorado Boulder	Boulder, CO
Assistant Professor of Computer Science	2014–Present
University of Maryland	College Park, MD
Assistant Professor in the Institute for Advanced Computer Studies	2011–2014
Assistant Professor of Information Studies	2010–2014
Postdoc	2009–2010
Advisor: Philip Resnik	

Education

Princeton University	Princeton, NJ
Ph.D. in Computer Science	2004 - 2010
Advisor: David Blei; Thesis: Linguistic Extensions of Topic Models	
California Institute of Technology	Pasadena, CA
B.S. in Computer Science and History (dual degree)	2000 - 2004

Selected Publications

Note: Students I have advised are underlined.

- Yuening Hu, Ke Zhai, Vlad Eidelman, and Jordan Boyd-Graber. Polylingual Tree-Based Topic Models for Translation Domain Adaptation. Association for Computational Linguistics, 2014 (26% Acceptance Rate).
- Alvin Grissom II, Jordan Boyd-Graber, He He, John Morgan, and Hal Daumé III. Don't Until the Final Verb Wait: Reinforcement Learning for Simultaneous Machine Translation. Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, 2014.
- 3. Viet-An Nguyen, Jordan Boyd-Graber, and Philip Resnik. Lexical and Hierarchical Topic Regression. Neural Information Processing Systems, 2013 (25% Acceptance Rate).
- 4. Yuening Hu, Jordan Boyd-Graber, Brianna Satinoff, and Alison Smith. Interactive Topic Modeling. *Machine Learning*, 2013.
- 5. Yuening Hu, <u>Ke Zhai</u>, Sinead Williamson, and **Jordan**Boyd-Graber. Modeling Images using Transformed
 Indian Buffet Processes. *International Conference of Machine Learning*, 2012 (27% Acceptance Rate).
- 6. <u>Ke Zhai</u>, **Jordan Boyd-Graber**, Nima Asadi, and Mohamad Alkhouja. **Mr. LDA: A Flexible Large**

- Scale Topic Modeling Package using Variational Inference in MapReduce. ACM International Conference on World Wide Web, 2012 (12% Acceptance Rate).
- 7. Jordan Boyd-Graber and Philip Resnik. Holistic Sentiment Analysis Across Languages: Multilingual Supervised Latent Dirichlet Allocation. *Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing*, 2010 (25% Acceptance Rate).
- 8. Jonathan Chang, **Jordan Boyd-Graber**, Chong Wang, Sean Gerrish, and David M. Blei. **Reading Tea Leaves: How Humans Interpret Topic Models**. *Neural Information Processing Systems*, 2009 (24% Acceptance Rate).
- Jordan Boyd-Graber, Christiane Fellbaum, Daniel Osherson, and Robert Schapire. Adding Dense, Weighted, Connections to WordNet. Proceedings of the Global Word-Net Conference, 2006.
- Jordan Boyd-Graber, Sonya S. Nikolova, Karyn A. Moffatt, Kenrick C. Kin, Joshua Y. Lee, Lester W. Mackey, Marilyn M. Tremaine, and Maria M. Klawe. Participatory design with proxies: Developing a desktop-PDA system to support people with aphasia. Computer-Human Interaction, 2006 (23% Acceptance Rate).